Nazmul Hassan

Software Engineer & Full-stack Developer

Phone +44 (0) 7451 0371 44

Email Nazmul.naaz96@gmail.com



Address Stepney Way, London E1 Great Britain

An extremely positive and individual & can stay focused and motivated. Responsible, dependable, and takes great pride in all my work. Can work both independently and in a team, proven from past work experience and academic experiences. Got rewarded BSc First Class Honours from the University of East London. Strong Coding experience in React JS, VUE, JAVA, MySQL, Spring MVC. Please click HERE to visit my portfolio and GitHub Repository is HERE.

EXPERIENCE

Feb 2019 - Present ServerDots

Web Application Developer

- Developed landing pages and online applications using React, VUE, Java, and MySQL scripting.
- Planned website development, converting mock-ups into usable web presence with React, HTML, JavaScript, and CSS coding.
- ♣ Provided front-end website development using WordPress, WIX, and other editing software.

Jul 2020 - Jan 2021 Sundarbon

IT Support Specialist

♣ Diagnosed, troubleshot, and resolved software issues with a 98% success rate.

Jan 2019 - Sep 2019 OreoStudio

Web Developer Intern

- Design and Building responsive website as client's requirements.
- ♣ Designed, implemented, and monitored web pages and sites for continuous improvement in a fast-paced environment.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Language: JAVA, React JS, HTML & CSS, JavaScript, Python, Dart (Flutter)
- ♣ Framework: Bootstrap, Django
- Database Management: MS Access, MySQL
- Operating system & Networking: KALI Linux
- Other: Spring Boot MVC, Spring Security, Flutter, iOS, Android.

PERSONALITY

- Self-Management
- Leadership & Responsible
- Friendly & Dependable

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATION

Sep 2017 - June 2020

University of East London (UEL)

Bachelor of Science Computer Science

- Awarded: 1st Class Honours
- Study Abroad: China, Computer Science
- Coursework Completed: Mobile App Development, Web Development, Cyber Security and Penetration Testing, Database Management, Data Structure and Algorithm & Advanced JAVA

Feb 2019 - Jul 2019

University of Electronic Science and Technology of China (UESTC)

Study Abroad Program

Replacement Program in China

June 2014 - May 2016

Bangladesh, Dhaka: Board of Higher Secondary Certificate

Higher Secondary H.S.C Science department (main subject – physics, chemistry, biology, mathematics
 & information and communication technology)

CERTIFICATIONS

- First Class Honours (Computer Science)
- ♣ LinkedIn Skill Assessment Badge

 JAVA | Python (Programming Language) | HTML

 | Cascading Style Sheet (CSS) JavaScript | React |

 Front-end Development | Linux | Git | MS Word | MS

 Excel | MS PowerPoint
- Hacker Rank Certification

LANGUAGES SKILL

- English Certified
- Bengali (Native)
- Hindi (Conversational)
- Urdu (Conversational)
- Italian (Basic)

TRAINING & PROJECT

University Project

University of East London (UEL)

- Final Year Project (Individual)
 - Application Developed with Python & C#
 - Platform Windows
 - Motive: Practice programming and solve problems.

SOURCE CODE

- Mobile App Development
 - App Developed with Flutter
 - Platform Android & iOS
 - Motive: Travel Blog for University of East London

SOURCE CODE

May 2021 - June 2021

IQUAD (InterQuest Accelerated Development)

Professional Training

♣ Front End: React JS

♣ Back End: JAVA, Spring Boot, Spring Security

Database: MySQL

↓ Tools: IntelliJ, Web Storm, Data Grip, MySQL Workbench

PROJECT COMPLITED

- ♣ Field Agent API
 - Developed with MySQL, JAVA & Spring Boot MVC.
 - Database & Table Created with MySQL.
 - CRUD Operation developed with JAVA

SOURCE CODE

- iQuad Academy API
 - Developed with MySQL, JAVA & Spring Boot MVC.
 - Database & Table Created with MySQL.
 - CRUD Operation developed with JAVA

SOURCE CODE

- ♣ iQuad Academy Front End
 - Developed with React JS.
 - Dependencies: React Routed Dom, React ICON
 - Framework: React Bootstrap

SOURCE CODE











